hey everyone welcome to another
interesting lesson in this TOS
automation course today we are going to
talk about the last identification
mechanism through which you can identify
different controls on your web
application so in tosa we have seen how
we can identify controls by Properties
by anchor control by image and the last
option which is there is called the
identification by
index so we are going to talk about it
uh it is also a useful mechanism when
you are trying to or you are not able to
identify controls uniquely using
properties or a anchor control or even
an image index could sometimes work out
uh better for you so let's see uh we are
going to use the same scenario uh since
we were using it for all the other
identification mechanisms uh we want to
enter some text into the Google search
and we want to click on this button
which is not unique on this application
right so we are going to uh use the
index in order to identify this control
and uh perform the operation which is
the
click so let's go to tosa and here again
um I'm in my module section and I'm
going to scan my application so that uh
we can add the module using all the
controls which we want uh for this
particular
module so uh again select the
application which is Google Chrome
application and click on
scan so once we are on the advanced view
um we are going to select our controls
which is the text box and um the Google
search button which is not unique um
obviously uh and we are going to use a
different mechanism for this Google
search button right so go to the
identify uh by option and here again um
you will see the last option which is
called index so select that and that
will open up a new window on the right
side which is called identify by index
so as you can see here uh it is showing
you a warning kind of sign uh and it is
telling to use the index if you cannot
choose the identification CR IIA to
uniquely identify the control and the
reason it is saying is uh it is not a
good idea to always use index as
identification mechanism it is not
always fullprof because um you are not
sure which index uh the particular
control is because there are similar
controls on the screen and it might
happen that it may use uh different
index than what you intend to use for a
particular control
right so that's the reason it shows you
that um it is not a stable option but
still if you want to use it you can
right um and tosa automatically
identifies which Index this particular
control is on the screen or on the
application so um you just need to
select that particular index if you want
to use it and as soon as you select it
you will see uh the message will change
that the selected item is unique so tosa
is able to uniquely identify the control
using the properties and the index right
uh so this control uses a constraint
index for identification right so uh
that's how the two mechanisms are
displayed here for Google search that's
what we are using to uniquely identify
it and we are going to save this module
right so close it
and that should build your module with
the two controls which are uniquely
identified and again the same procedure
so this time uh we are going to use the
index option so I'm going to change this
name just to make it more clear right uh
and add a particular test case here
[Music]
so Google search and then just add the
module here to get it
working and let's enter the values here
which is the test step values uh again
the same values which we have been using
for all the other scenarios right and
let's go ahead and run this now just to
test whether this option is working as
expected or not
so as you can see it is able to perform
uh the required operation and it has
generated the required output right uh
you will see the same thing on the
scratchbook after um it has executed
right so it will show the T step has
passed so uh this was another option uh
which is good or is a good option to use
when you are not able to identify it
using the other mechanisms but you
should follow the hierarchy which is
present in tosa right so in the identify
by option you will see there is a
particular hierarchy the first option is
identify by properties then it goes to
Anchor then it goes to image and the
last option is Index right so generally
uh you should follow this but depending
on the application depending on your
scenario you can always uh choose any of
the options
right um but uh choose your options
wisely when you are trying to identify
your controls because uh your whole
automation execution could depend on
that particular mechanisms which you are
choosing while building your automation
pack so this was all about uh how you
can identify controls by index um hope
this was useful uh we soon come up with
more interesting Tsar lessons in the
coming up weeks so keep watching and do
subscribe be to our Channel and we'll
see you in the next session